that the team said okay it was developed
by third party we had enough of fixing
the bux there let's just decommission it
and put it behind our very more secure
code base so like we actually managed to
get a product the commission which is
nice achievement I I mean po people if
they know the J I don't
[Music]
know
hey guys quick reminder before we hop
into this week's episode word fence is
still running their holiday bug
Extravaganza through December 20th and
paying 6.25 times their normal Bounty
amounts over the past week over 200
critical thinking listeners have set up
their WordPress testing environment and
the word fence team reports multiple
crits turned in by critical thinking
listeners so I really appreciate it you
guys you guys have been crushing it um
the best way to support the podcast is
to hack on our sponsors and you guys
have been doing just that so if you guys
want to get in on the action if you
haven't already head over to ctbb doow
WF for wordfence ctbb doow WF you can
find the program sign up link there and
some Docker install scripts to get you
started and of course when you do
finally turn in your report don't forget
to mention critical thinking for that
extra 10% bonus on top of your normal
Bounty um with that I guess we'll get to
the episode this week we've got guest G
nogly on for the second time we're going
to be discussing the live hacking event
scene and some bugs we found
collaborating together over a week of
hacking in person hope you guys
enjoy all righty man round
two we uh we just got settled in the uh
in the sun room here at my house and we
recorded for 15 minutes and then we
realized that the mute button on M on
nogi's mic is was on so once again
welcome to the podcast thank you happy
to be for the second time and let's hope
this one my mic is walking it's too
complex for me this we can very
expensive microphone um all right man so
let's see we can talk about a bunch of
live hacking events stuff and we should
I think and I think we will but I think
before we get into that let's talk about
some of the hacking we've done over the
past couple days um
because we I've been working together on
some hacking stuff for what probably
three or four days um and I think we
found some pretty interesting stuff
um so let's uh let's talk about the WW
root.zip thing that you came upon and
how we kind of exploited that so give me
give me a little bit of an intro into
that yeah so it was just one random
domains suddenly pops up on my slack
automation with
Expos backup file zip file whatever you
can call it just it's nothing fancy just
random nuclear template so when you see
a backup file I mean first thing you
would want to report it right away you
know so it won't be dup or anything else
and then all the efforts will go will go
down and while we open it was asp.net
app full of source code bin files config
files web. config and so on so nothing
really I mean you you wouldn't find like
AWS credentials out of nowhere in the
source code or like Pi leakage of all
users some stuff like that were some
juicy stuffff some Source Cod but still
you would want maybe to take it you know
one step further not only the the
probably the exposure is a critical for
itself but maybe we can find more stuff
to to do with it to do that yeah so I
mean source code exposure at that level
definitely I think is a critical in and
of itself but a lot of programs want to
see impact from that too um and so you
know obviously we went and got that
impact so we'll talk about that but um
the the initial Discovery I kind of want
to double click into that as well is
that was that a custom nuclei template
that you had or was that a one of the
defaults that were in the list or is do
you have so many now it's kind of hard
to keep track yeah I think it's just the
default backup files templates okay
that's awesome so and then how fast did
you respond to this uh after because
you've got automation running these
nuclei scans across all the targets that
you have in your system uh you know at a
certain Pace how fast did you have to
respond to be the first one to report
this I think it depends some of the
stuff you have to be really really fast
like dog config for example you can't
let it lay down for more than half an
hour maybe or or five minutes until
someone will pick it up but this one I'm
not sure I was that fast about it
because it was just a random template I
I mean I didn't I don't do much of root
cause analysis like whether the host was
just new and that's why I got it because
it's not a d i mean I got I got a re
eventually it was like two or three
weeks ago um but I mean certainly you
want you want to report your findings
that T than one day after you after you
get notification or something like that
so that one I'm not sure if it was like
rapid the same second but it always
depends if you find a new host if the
host just became publicly accessible or
if you know some something happened so
yeah I'm not really sure how long it
took but it wasn't rap it wasn't in a
minute I guess for that one yeah no that
makes sense I I think you know when
you're doing automation scanning like
that with nuclei you kind of got to be
pretty quick to scan all of your targets
as well and so for that are you are you
using um are you Distributing those
scans or are you actually just have one
box just like pounding all of these host
with nuclei yeah so I use axum to
distribute like most of the heavy scan
that I want to do first I also just
created a Shockwave box for like I I
literally went manually to all through
all of my programs on H one and
backgound and I collected a list of 90
programs that I I consider good paying
well while card good teams and then I
will just add the only their R domains
to like a more dedicated scanning
feature that we can see like changes
more more frequent like easier way to
see with UI and stuff like that so I
like there is the entire program data
set that someone can suddenly expose a
backup file and we can find good money
and there is the program that I know
okay we need to keep close eyes on the
close eyes on them for changes because
they develop and ship new line of codee
every few days and they have good
bounties so like I divided my scanning
and my targets to two different uh nice
so you've got sort of like the the S
tier programs and then you
know gotcha and then the rest no that
that makes sense and that incentivizes
programs to really you know pay some
good bounties because hackers like this
are like nogly are doing that sort of
thing so that's cool um Shockwave you
mentioned there I'm GNA give you 30
seconds you know un uninterrupted to do
a Shockwave promotion right now yeah so
so so look look right there into the
camera and talk talk to us about your
product Shockwave yeah basically we try
to help companies small or big just give
us your R domain give us your company
name we'll show you all your assets
Technologies very easy to see with one
clicks very easy to scan with your own
templates even with nuclei or whatever
scanners you'd like to see also for
companies or campaigns or projects who
wants to launch a bu Bounty campaign or
like a way to interact with the with
their external researchers through
comments and markdown we have that very
EAS
integrated and set up everything is in
the website so no I mean no nons sinere
just you can see and so so it's sort of
like an ASM plus bug Bounty interface of
challenges VIP Pro I mean you can invite
your top researchers to see all your
assets you know instead of giving Excel
file or Google sheet file or Google doc
so you can add the researchers to the
actual ASM interface as well they have
like only view only you know I mean
imagine like an ak1 or back out program
instead of giving you CSV file and you
pass it run htpx Go stuff just have your
entire researches and you know you can
just skip the Recon focus on manual
that's awesome man no I I totally dig
that so yeah definitely uh what's the
what's the domain where people can find
out shock. Cloud Shockwave docl check it
out y'all um so you've got Shockwave you
know your Shockwave instance set up um
and we get this ping you report it as
quickly as you can you know this one was
a little bit slower uh but the whole
source code for this app is sort of
leaked in in the uh document route um
and the team comes back and they want
more more impact with it and no actually
they I mean I reported it 11 days ago
then no one no not rewear on it sadly
and then the team reopened it and like
three days ago and said hey is it still
working so I'm like I'm not sure wait
did you fix it was it fixed by its own
do you want me to retest or it's like
hanging in between so I said let's we
can still exploit it so let's see let's
see what we can get out of it yeah and
and obviously the source code disclosure
is problem but we want to try to bring
actual tangible impact to the asset as
it is currently because if they had said
if they had had somebody delete that
file and then they go back and look at
your report they're like well we didn't
make a change because of your report
so I mean they might even fix it like
it's resolved now we can't access the
file but yeah it's still not resolved
you know if someone got the file it's
like yeah you can still get the stuff
that we we manag to the end of world
yeah especially in those ASP
environments because what what we ended
up doing with that was uh the backup the
zip file backup had the prod machine key
in the web.config file um for that
application and then what we were able
to do was use yso serial to craft a
deserialization view State uh or a view
state that would get deserialized and
executes a malicious code um and then
that proved that we were able to
actually turn it into our CE and that
they also hadn't fully resolved this bug
because they hadn't rotated the prod
machine so some bugs I mean they can
resolve the exposure but they need to
rotate some keys and stuff it's like
inent response after the initial
Discovery yeah and and sometimes you can
get a second Bounty for that um you know
if they really don't do a good job of of
cleaning up after them so that's another
you know kind of tip to keep in the port
fron your mind but something that was
interesting to me technically about this
bug um that as as you know we started
collaborating on actually shelling the
box and getting an rce um was that that
aspx file that we sent this request to
uh with the view state it actually had
some source code in it that said view
State enabled
false yeah and and and so you know you
when looking at that you might think
that the abew state isn't getting parsed
but uh I found in this article somewhere
that back in 2014 they just said all
right we're just going to ignore this
parameter exactly and they're going to
parse it anyway so um you're still able
to get that uh even if the view state is
set to false um specifically within the
document or within that specific file um
and then so let's talk about the second
piece that happened there so now we've
popped the rce and we're good but now
there's still a bunch of source code you
know that we've got access to and for us
that looked like a couple aspx files um
and we were able to expand that that
scope quite a bit but by looking through
the source code that was there and
finding that there were a couple
dlls uh in that in that source code that
were being referenced in the aspx files
and inside and those dlls um were were
created uh using uh asp.net and so they
could be reversed using a software
called Peak uh and so we we loaded it up
into Peak and we got access to a massive
amount of source code that was powering
this whole application um and it depends
you know they might bring this asset
inside the network uh and I I might
advise them to bring the the asset
inside the network I wouldn't double
down like spend the months on it before
we see like the reaction to the to the
second barg you know see what what do
they want to do with the hor yeah it's
important to be outside like so so in
scenarios like this you normally wait to
go down that additional exploitation
path um assuming we have permission from
the program to use the source code and
that sort of thing um you normally to
see how they are going to deal with that
scenario before you go down that path of
extra exploitation yeah not in terms of
holding bug but in terms of not spending
time for nothing you know like let's see
how the reaction and let's continue from
there because we don't want to spend two
weeks on bugs that you will fix with one
one go or will avoid one Bounty for so
in in that sense yeah you got to try to
avoid those scenarios um so that was a
fun one that we found uh let's see what
is uh what I mean the only reason that
iact I mean we saw the secrets and there
wasn't I said there was no like a ACC
key or and or password but I saw the P
machine key and then I just remembered
on the back of my head some tweets of I
think shabs used to do a lot of.net or
other people and they always say if you
find web config if you find v machine Q
RC so like you have this on the back of
your head and say okay yeah Justin you
want maybe you you could dig a little
bit further there so that's it when you
get a PR machine key feel free to reach
out to
Justin and uh and he will he will try to
get that RC for you um no that's good
man and I think it's it's a good you
know various hackers have different
different skills and um you know I would
have never found that WWE root.zip just
because I don't scan for that sort of
thing on a regular basis and then we can
kind of put our minds together to
actually get the rce so it's a good
collab um the next interesting bug that
we found was this Swagger file that
turned into an S3 bucket arbitrary read
so uh talk to me about the the I guess
initial Recon and Discovery process for
that yeah I mean you you always like to
to look for Swagger files either for
trying the xsss which barely work these
days most of them are fixed unless
someone wants to find a new zero day on
Swagger and it will be very very good
very good
one so instead of just looking for
Access sometimes you have
unauthenticated access to execute API
calls and stuff like that so the the one
host that we found was like very weird
API calls there just list tons of data
which looked like it's Dev or them but
it was production data actually and we
had to piece out like to assemble a lot
of small pieces to get to some impact
out of the host but we found like a good
eventually we found like a good leader
that uh we could get directory list
access to an internal s bucket by and
because we we were able to get a
pre-signed URL on a pass like not on an
end point and then it just gave us
access to the to the host if you want to
expand a little bit about the yeah yeah
so so I I guess the first step of that
was starting to sort of recreate the
um the requests and try to piece
together the logic because a Swagger
file is great because it gives you the
sort of technical details but it doesn't
always kind of explain all the lingo
behind everything and uh all of the
purposes of of the various functions
actually there were dos there but it's
an internal domain like they said if you
want to read about how it works check
this internal domain and we're like oh
dra
can't can't do that um so we were trying
to piece it together and it it was
actually a couple layers deep right so
in order to find the initial uh in order
to find the string I guess the format of
the ID that we needed to give to the
endpoint that ended up leaking the the
pre-signed URL to the S3 bucket we had
to go through a c two other API calls to
get uh to list all the objects
associated with some stuff and then pick
one of the subobjects within there get
more details on that object and then
that leaked the ID and then we used that
ID to get access to the S3 bucket
arbitrarily um so it goes to show you
know when you're looking for these when
you're seeing these Swagger apis pop up
you know sometimes it's a little bit
unfortunate because you go and you check
them out and and then it says off
required off required off required but
in scenarios where off is not required
it it definitely pays to sort of double
click into those read through and kind
of experiment we probably spent what
like two hours playing around with those
end points yeah um and and I think we'll
get a good Bounty for it so that that
should definitely be interesting to see
how that one pins out because we just
found it like earlier today or yesterday
I mean the the whole thing is that
question what you respon what the
respones and what you see returns like
from your actions like I try to put a
full URL there like with an actual log
end point and then I got like not found
like the end point directory wasn't
found I said okay what happen if I just
remove the endpoint and check the
directory and then it gave you full
access the directory with pre signed URL
so that's like question everything you
see okay we can't find this can we find
can we make the API do other yeah and
sort of ideate you know on top of that
too like even even as you're thinking
you can be you know deleting various
paths and seeing how far it'll let you
Traverse back up in that scenario
because we had an ID that contained
paths um that we were kind of working
with and so uh that was that was the way
we ended up
actually popping it there um so yeah I
guess Swagger Swagger files do you often
actually inspect the content of the
Swagger files that you're searching for
are you just kind of looking to pop xss
is with the Swagger files how does that
play into your normal automation I'm not
doing routinely scanning for them it's
like there are thousands so it's like
one of the most popular end points for
like random you know that is common for
every program around the world once in a
while if it's interesting program or if
I want to do some manual hacking check
swagers Less in the automation side side
of things yeah no that makes sense um
I'm going to go ahead and do the uh Hey
Google turn on the sun room
lights there we go wow look at that look
look at that look at that technology
coming into play for those of you
actually listening to this podcast as an
audio medium uh we just turned on all
the lights in the sun room uh voice yes
by voice um so yeah that was that was a
great bug and then I kind of want to
talk to you as well about and sort of
debate with you the URL
do domain we're going to need to bleep
that one but that's the one that we
spent I spent a bunch of time on and you
told me to give up on and then I ended
up confirming that it is vulnerable but
uh it's going to take at least 70 days
worth of uh of HTTP requests to actually
pop this bug because of the uh sort of
cryptographic complexity of the
vulnerability um
so this domain we you found just through
normal Recon and then you passed it off
to me right can you elaborate on that at
all or we found some it's like a domain
for wellknown Target and they have a lot
of subdomains and we we found the one
domain which is was pointing to a thir
part it was just a login panel then you
see the version down there it was like
one
1.74 or 1.7 yeah 1.74 and then the the
one thing you do the first thing you do
is look for cves you know for that
version and we just saw critical cve Sol
for version 1.73 or pouched in 1.74 so
we are right on the verge of okay is it
vable or not like that's the Val so yeah
in order to confirm it there was public
CV public PC which basically tells you
okay you need to brute force a lot until
you get a collision like PHP typing yeah
it's it was a PHP type juggling pug yeah
and and it required you to generate a
hash that starts with zero e and this an
md5 hash zero e and then every other
character in the whole hash is a number
rather than a letter um which is very
very tricky to make happen um but we
were running I was working with another
hacker and we were kind of running the
math on it and he says he thinks we can
do it in roughly 70 days of brute
forcing non-stop so and it would be it
would be a pretty impactful bug if it
actually popped so uh I'm gonna set up a
script and just kind of have it run
because why not I think for those stuff
maybe if it's a good team and I think
here it's a good team you could try and
ask them like maybe in the chat in the
back of one of your reports or like in a
new report hey I mean I'm pretty sure
it's vulnerable because we we actually
diffed the GitHub version and saw that
it's on the vulnerable version I mean
would you accept it without me V forcing
it for 70 days like killing the server
and stuff like that sometimes filling up
all of the log files yeah um yeah and
and I think just to clarify or to dive a
little deeper on what we did to confirm
it was vulnerable even though the
advisory said it was patched in
1.7.4 what we ended up doing was going
to the GitHub because it's an open
source
software um and we uh I guess hosted
within the organization it's an open
source software um and we found that
there was a modification to the read me.
HTML file that was done right before uh
the change that fixed the critical
vulnerability and it was modifying a
lowercase age to an uppercase age that's
it um and when we went to the read me.
HTML file we ended up finding that it
was the lower case AG still confirming
that it had not been that the
vulnerability had not been patched uh
that there had been other changes made
in that same version uh but they had
when they pulled down that version it it
wasn't to the point point where it had
yeah had had the patch in it yet so we
were able to identify that it should
still be vulnerable yeah that's a good
idea you know we could we could reach
out to the program Ian it wouldn't I
mean worst case they tell you exploit it
that's the worst case the best case
scenario is they accept it and Patch
which is easy so what best case you get
the Bounty which you deserve worst case
you need to do what you want to do
anyway so like yeah maybe it's a better
idea to let them know yeah I'll I'll
reach out to them see if we can get it
to pop but I spent I because the exploit
that that was out there the act the PC
that was published was a HTP yeah it was
it was only for
HTTP and uh the server that we were
interacting with would only communicate
over htps so you had to rewrite the
exploit for htps compatible which wasn't
very tricky actually you told me to do
have chat GPT do it and I was like very
funny and then I I told chat TBT to do
it and it like generated almost all of
the code I just only had to make a
couple modifications hey guys if our
weekly episode isn't enough bug Bounty
content for you then you'll definitely
want to join the critical thinking
podcast Discord there's tons of channels
in there where people are asking and
answering questions collaborating on
exploits and even developing tools
together also for those of you that are
interested in supporting the Pod we've
got premium subscriber tiers that get
access to things like amas and master
classes so if you're interested in that
head over to ctbb Dosh show/ Discord
ctbb doow Discord to get in on some of
the action all right back to the
show then you know there was the whole
process of like okay is it something
wrong with this exploit or is it
something wrong with this you know the
server and it's not actually vulnerable
right or is it just taking time and at
the end of the day um you know me and
this other hacker that that went after
it uh sort of determined that the server
was definitely vulnerable uh which is
going to take a bunch of time so uh I
got to go set up a script after this to
actually continuously monitor that and
reach out the team to the team maybe see
yeah that we don't actually disturb the
services there exactly um yeah all right
so that's that's what we had for the
bugs that we found let me see if there's
anything else on here oh yeah do you
want to tell them uh no I'll do the
honors and the S3 bucket was filled with
drum roll please credit card transaction
data um so should be should be pretty
juicy when the team gets that one and
gets that one triaged um so all right
let's uh let's take we're going to go
get some dinner here shortly I think but
uh let's go ahead and discuss the live
hacking event season that we had in
2023 and then also go and talk about the
new live hacking event standards that
dropped uh for 2024 not too long ago
because they made some changes that are
looking quite good um
first I want you to tell me about two
live hacking events that you've been to
this year buades and uh actually let's
do three because these are the ones that
I'm the most salty to have missed okay
buenos SES that's the uh Ambassador
World Cup we got the uh Facebook event
in Singapore no no no in in uh South
Korea that's right and um and then we
have uh hacker one Las Vegas which I
didn't go to uh by choice which which
was which was a hard decision to make
but I think the right one for me at the
time um so start with buenus SAS and
that was an ambassador World Cup event
tell me a little bit about that and how
that sized up to normal life hacking
events that we that we go to on a
regular basis Yeah so basically this is
the second edition of the ak1 Ambassador
World Cup the first year there wasn't
any live haing event but was very good
event you know Bounty wise it the
biggest perk was and still is that it
gives more people opportunities to get
to Live acing Events they usually save
some slots from the competition to to to
show up for the team or it's Community
Edition that they nominate for the
events I got my first event invite just
from participating and doing well in the
Ambassador World Cup last year so this
year we were in the group stage with
Team Spain which we actually batted for
the first place eventually and one part
of Team USA I don't know if you I think
you were there maybe no no it wasn't
mine it was uh it was the West Coast no
it was uh the it was so Team USA is is
split into multiple different teams yeah
my my
team how many teams did you have I I
only had one team no how many teams did
the US have the US had two teams yeah so
you we were against you no you were
against USA team Oh you mean in the
beginning of of the World Cup yeah oh
yeah yeah the beginning not not I
thought were only on okay okay so you
guys didn't the the other team the the
West Coast they lost that's right they
got knocked out on the other side so
you're right you were against me in the
beginning uh uh and freaking knocked us
out first round uh it was you and Spain
were also in that same bracket right so
you know U us zero had it hard from the
beginning uh because we had up against
such uh such strong competition um yeah
I mean we were very happy in the
quarterfinals this year that they
announced to the eight ambassadors that
were left okay we didn't know if it
would be like a knockout for the final
in person like two teams 24 members each
or it would be like four teams so then
they announced before the quarterfinal
stage that they would be four teams so
it was very good motivation for the
quarterfinals we were against Singapore
in the quarterfinal and we beat them so
that was good then in the quarterfinal
then the semi-final was online as well
we beat Team France there it was hard
battle there as well and then for the
finals we four teams flew 12 to 10
members from each team and then it was
the fight for the first place and the
fight for the third place Nepal and
France for the third place us and Israel
and Spain for the first place and it was
the same Target same environment same L
Vibes as always but like you know you
battle for different different prizes
okay so all of the the top four teams so
first second third and fourth you know
whatever undecided places they were in
yet they were all hacking on the same
Target so you were duping each other on
the same Target and did it have a dup
window or uh time to
remember if there was a dup window it
wasn't a big one because I don't
remember I no I don't think there was no
D oh really yeah I think it was
sometimes you could say welcome change
because I found Lo for J in five minutes
after after the event started so that
was like super crazy so so did you just
like load up the domains into your into
your shock wave tool and then it just
like yeah I do that but actually I found
it randomly not from that like from my
routine scans just Lo for J out of no on
in scope domain before the targets were
announced like before we knew the
customer I I got an alert 30 minutes
before it was in person we were actually
in Portugal at the time and the Spain
team were around me and they told them
hey I just found Lo for J got 10K after
2 hours they paid me like so some good
things they did they pay you right away
and no dup window so those are like I
mean dup window you could say sometimes
it's good sometimes it's bad but they
pay you also right away and not only the
event so it was very very nice to start
the event like that okay so so they
actually the whole time they were paying
they weren't waiting to do payouts until
person wow so you're already coming to
the event already having a lot of the
Bounties in
I bet that for Environ actually at the
in bu because you were you were already
paid out in a lot of ways you were kind
of I mean I don't know maybe the
competition was still ring one end yes
but in the second end because the point
system is not reputation based and not
Bounty based it was only it's like
severity and volume based so we didn't
really know the rankings it was like
internally for the h one team they had
to do a lot of calculations maybe for
next year they will have a proper
leaderboard just to display the points
so our team was like first second and
third like three people me Matan and
nishai on the bounties but it doesn't
mean that we are going to win because
like 10 like four mediums are one
critical or three mediums is one crit so
even if we have 10 crits and they 50
mediums it's like it's even better than
that they had crits also as well but we
had like the most crits so you don't
really know if you're winning or losing
on side which it adds a little bit of
suspense but I mean the Bounty sometimes
is good to get before
so I mean with with that then do you
prefer the live hacking event based
money sort of order of payouts or I
guess like at the live hacking events
the leaderboard is based off of how much
money you've earned right do you prefer
that or do you prefer this system how
much Bounty like like today like we have
today how much Bounty you earn I think
it's the most H it's the best no farming
no no other stuff that you could do but
I mean team competition it's interesting
to have a point system I guess it makes
sense to have points and not bounty
Bounty base because there are some
targets like PayPal or
like like onean show targets you know
like Alex bson no joash people like that
they get a Target they would easily win
alone with one hand you know so some
sometimes you need like team competition
with point system and it makes sense in
this that that makes sense man so so
you've got the Ambassador world cup
seems like it was very L with a little
bit of changes to it you know for the
man
yeah some experiments that seemed to
have gone well um talk to me about the
uh South Korea event with with Facebook
because like man was I bummed to not
have been able to go to that event I had
a bachelor party that weekend um so I
wasn't able to make it out there but it
seemed awesome and I think you said out
of all the destinations that you've been
to for live hacking events South Korea
was one of your favorite right yeah it's
very good The Vibes there are very good
very chill like it's very nice country
and I got reached out from one of
Facebook's former program managers they
wanted to invite like they have their
Inner Circle they have leagues they have
gold leagues Diamond league but they
also wanted like other LH Hackers from
akan from bak and so on so we got into
the event me Joel and technog gig
decided no jo is techn GE me Jo me Joel
and space decided to collab a and see if
we can find anything and actually just
as I was on the train to get to catch
the flight we managed to land together
EXs on dub du dub which is like super
rare even you know Yousef is one of the
best tackers on Facebook said it's super
rare to see see stuff so we got paid
good and it was very very nice to get
that but also I mean it's nice to see
events from other companies as well see
how they manage it how some stuff that
they do differently or not but it was
very good experience there can you can
you talk about the xss a little bit um I
guess vaguely was it a reflected xss or
a DA based xss was some D post message
stuff basically we found embedded inside
up they had some service which was open
source
and I think it was excal probably I
think space is filled actually a zero
day for it one day I think they fix it
already so Joel was already mes we were
messing with some code ql stuff to
reverse engineer so he took that code
put it in code ql he saw some XS Inc I
mean he told him there is X but I mean
if CQ tells you there's XS you're far
away from actually seeing the pop up so
we reached out to spaceon and he told us
that he found a very very very similar
bug on other big company so he just
looked at it okay modification here
modification there yes public blog about
another very similar it just did all the
way so took him 20 minutes and we got
our very good back for the event dang
man that's crazy so Joel is actually
hitting it with C that's that's an
interesting uh uh approach to that I
haven't I haven't used code ql at all
especially not in a JavaScript context
text that that that seems like an
interesting I'm not sure if it was
JavaScript for for the uh Library must
have been right it was like a third
party product embedded into into
Facebook I don't remember which code
it's like one of the code C gotcha
gotcha that that that's really cool no I
dig that and and that was that was I
mean I imagine you guys found other bugs
that event but that was the crowning
Jewel of the event for y'all yeah I I
mean it's hardware and it's called
Facebook so it's like very very hard to
find some good bags I had some few minor
ones but that was the the big one
man I want I wanted to go to it so bad
um all right so that's that's the
Singapore event I'm not Singapore I'm
sorry South Korea again I keep on
getting that mixed up in my head um the
last one Vegas missed this one because
of Mariah's birthday uh I I'm going to
try to come every other year but it
always goes over her birthday so uh
sometimes I got to stay home and uh and
enjoy the Family Life over here but this
year kind of tell me how Vegas went and
what were your what were your thoughts
on the Live Hack event yeah so The Vibes
are very good it was two very big and
good customers from previous L as well
and so on great bonuses the great people
that came along it was very we had some
small fun challenges between ourselves
as well me and the other people for
example we found France Rosen a little
board which is very rare to see him a
board because he got so many bounties so
he didn't know what to do so I was I was
fighting some xss and literally I took
my computer I gave him the URL I set up
a timer of 10 minutes and I had 2K in
cash I think dollars and I put it near
him there's a picture of it somewhere or
video and I told him okay you have 10
minutes to get to bypass the WAFF which
I I knew he wouldn't be able to do which
is he can do everything but I think I
saw this one he couldn't if you bypass
it you get a 2K cash H because I needed
it for a BG please he did it no he
couldn't he couldn't oh no he made way
more so it's okay that would been
ridiculous if he had bypassed it in 10
minutes yeah because it was like very
very difficult off and other it would be
a zero day on some very big big stuff go
but it was fun fun Challenge and good
bounties good bugs we managed to find
some very some very critical bugs even
one of the products that I was hitting
was just decommissioned after the event
I mean we were able to find so many bugs
and critical ones on this very important
component of one of the product that the
team said okay it was developed by third
party we had enough of fixing the box
there let's just decommission it and put
it behind our very more secure code base
so like we actually managed to get a
product the commission which is nice
achievement I mean two people if they
not the J I don't
know I don't know that does feel good
though when when you just see the host
like disappear and never appear again I
mean I I'm I lost some I lose some
bounties now because of that because the
host is dead now yeah but
it was fun experience yeah hopefully
they won't do that to our our vul that
we mentioned earlier with where we got
the source code now that would be that
would be great if we could hold on to
that and keep keep trying to find buds
there um all right man let's uh let's go
get some dinner soon but um I want to
talk about the live hacking event
standards that dropped so I'm going to
go ahead and pull it up here on my phone
and you can pull it up on your computer
yeah it's NE season starting now yeah so
the new season for live hacking events
is uh is coming up uh in 202
we both got our uh invites today for a
live hacking event in January which we
can't give any other details on right
now but we we're pretty hyped for so
that should be great um I took some
notes Here I kind of read through it and
took some notes Here the first thing
that I kind of saw that looked most
interesting was they're uh offering up
to 10 researchers
invites uh with this condition hacker
one platform performers over the last
one 180 days rearch researchers with 75%
or greater submissions rated high or
critical in more than five total hits in
that time frame uh and then this list is
prioritized by total rewards in the last
80 uh 180 days so it looks like they're
looking for
hackers that have pretty much just
submitted high in critical
reports in the past six months with over
a
75% amount of that right and they the
the impact requirements from everything
yeah impact they started they pulled it
last year I think actually because it
was like hard 22 impact which eventually
didn't make sense because you don't want
I mean collab basically because collab
takes your impact down as well T so you
can't tell people not to collab so it
was good it's good that they took it off
from there this stat it's a little it's
still hard here to understand because it
it tells you to report less medium and
lows bug I mean most some people have
this by default above 75% higher CR
think I have above 75 probably cosmin
have it Alex verson those guys probably
answer that criteria but it doesn't
reflect on the leader vs right on the H
one leader vs today because if you check
top 10 I think nine of them are not
having only high in crit wow that that's
crazy I definitely do not have above 75%
high in crit reported as I report you
know lots of mediums and lows just as a
part of my normal flow um is that is
that something that you're doing
intentionally are you not reporting lows
Med I'm reporting mediums I I don't find
I wish I would mation find more mediums
than lows but it's more money but I mean
this year I found less medium and lows
but if I find I I of course I will
report them yeah I mean this that I
think maybe they could remove like let's
say remove the Restriction of 75% but
have a hard Gap okay you have to have 10
crits or 10 highend crits paid and also
minimum Bounty like at least 50k for six
at least 100K for six months that would
be also could be a good barrier or no I
really I really like that I would love
to see them move this top performer on
the platform
to strictly bounties earned from highs
in crits vulnerabilities like if they're
looking for people that are dropping a
lot of highs in crits then you should
just look at highs and crits and then
sort by amount of money earned yeah from
those highs and crits reports right
because you're essentially what that
proves is you're finding lots of highs
and crits on targets that are paying
highs and crits well so I think that
would accomp accomplish their so you
don't want to have like one person say
Corbin find say one 500k bug on offens
like let's say find 200k bug so you want
to have like 10 you need to have like 10
of this in the period and you need to
have the Bounty average or the Bounty
Bounty start yeah totally agree with
that um but there's a good opportunity
there because I feel like there's
probably not as many people that are
submitting 75% higher crits so if you
really if like your life goal is to get
invited to a live hacking event then it
might be worthwhile to um maybe pass
these bugs off to a friend or trade bugs
off with a friend uh or and just focus
on submitting highs and crits for six
months if you want to get invited um the
next sort of section that I thought we
might have some some conversation about
is uh up to three researchers that are
new to live hacking events and this is
researchers who have shown criticality
consistency and contributed to the
community across hacker one platform but
have not participated in a live hacking
event previously hackers must have the
below criteria greater than 5K rep
greater than five signal um and so it
seems like that is not too crazy of a
Criterion there right like there are a
lot of people that have above 5K rep and
above five signal yeah I mean nowadays I
think I think when ak1 first began and I
wasn't still hacking on the ples signal
was more in because there were way more
na this days I think there was way less
Naas only if you're really spamming you
get Na and your signal is getting
affected but about 5k it's fair like if
you have 5K it means you did something I
mean I would say some people could have
5K only from vdps as well but it's easy
to filter if someone has no bounties but
about 5k I think Ali actually got his
first liveing evet invite because of
that he was like new to live backing
event and he got got a chance as a
community choice this year so now they
have this CR and he did very well on the
event that participated in so it's a
good it's a good good one to have yeah
yeah no I really like this one and I
think it'll bring some fresh blood in
and the the Criterion is not so um
difficult that it excludes a bunch of
people so I I imagine what this would
look like is either a lottery or some
sort of um Choice system because there's
going to be a lot of people that meet
this criteria right um and then there's
also obviously of course the local
hacker thing so if you're you know if a
live hacking event is getting hosted in
your city there's a chance that you'll
get invited to that simply because
you're local and you don't require
flight and hotel and that sort of thing
so that's something to be on the lookout
for the most CH the biggest change that
did see I don't think you mention in the
on the Docks but I see it here so
basically from last year they introduced
a new criteria to have up to top 10
researchers from the past events so they
take the past three events they
accumulate the top 10 for each event
then they take the top 10 of the
bounties like individual bounties from
the last we event and they have another
leaderboard and they invite the top 10
so this year they made it 20 okay so
there are 20 people either you got mvh
best H exterminator any other reward or
top 10 based on bounties it really helps
you like you got the chance once if you
will be on the top five top 10 get
awards every event you will be there
again which is very good I mean you
don't want like to be invited to an
event do very well and then you wouldn't
answer any other criteria so you would
be G so that's I think the biggest
speaking speaking from the heart right
now aren't you ugly
with five performance for all of 2023
right no no it was I mean in the in
Vegas I was top 10 because it was two
Targets but I was top 10 across most of
them but yeah I mean it helps you to
also push harder when you get invited
and not just lay back and and chill like
try to do a good job to get invited to
the next one and also this year they
mentioned specifically that they they I
think they saw a little bit of trend of
people who really don't find any bus or
don't even try I mean to have and I
think specifically mention if we saw
people who were invited and didn't
really even try or something they they
take it into consideration as well for
yeah full event yeah no I think the
trying piece is is pivotal because I
think if you don't try it's just
disrespectful and it's it's squandering
an opportunity that a lot of other
people would fight really hard to get
their hands on um so I'm definitely glad
to see that as well and I guess within
the live hacking group circle that that
extra you know top 10 piece is really
interesting unfortun I you know they
called out specifically in here that the
um mvh you know would be included in the
uh in the top 10 list or whatever but I
don't see that same little caveat that
they've had in years past of MBH is
being invited for the live hacking
events for the next year um in there
anymore so uh I guess there so many now
you know lot ofh and a lot of events
like plus five events a year so it I
mean you could have like 10 Award
winners an event if you collab for
exterminator for best collab so it's
like it's hard now guest it's definitely
becoming more tricky um and then the
last one that I wanted to to call out
here was the plus one nominations which
I still think is one of the best ways to
get invited to a live hacking event if
that's your goal is to collaborate well
with somebody who gets an invite to a
live hacking event and then get that
plus one nomination and get chosen for
that and for that they don't lay out the
specific stats that will result in their
decision you know because they can't
accept everyone who's nominated but uh
you know if you have a good hacker one
profile and you get nominated as a as a
plus one you certainly have an
opportunity one of the things that I saw
here though was multiple nominations
does not increase the priority excuse me
yeah does not increase the priority to
ensure consistency and fair review so
that's one thing that we've kind of
talked about before at at the top level
of like okay we've got this specific
friend that wants to be invited you know
we all want him there and so we all put
him as a plus one you know in hopes that
he'll get he'll get chosen but they've
made us specific caveat this year that
that is not the case sense yeah so that
that is that does make it a little bit
more difficult to sort of bruteforce
that process and try to force the people
you want to get chosen in but um you
know I'm definitely looking looking for
this this plus one nominations thing is
one of the key um pieces of the live
hacking event sauce in finding people
who are able to perform at live hacking
events uh you know through referral
essentially so I'm I'm continuing to to
look forward to just seeing how that
that is going to play out I think in
general we need to be grateful to have
events at all and even to be invited
it's like very it's crazy opportunity to
have a good time find good bugs learn
like so it's very every time we get one
and I hope there will be as many as as
possible and also with background
Integrity I hope they will take to like
they will do well also in this year for
in terms of liveing events and yeah I'm
looking forward for the next the next
year yeah me too man for sure um all
right the last thing that I wanted to
cover before we we get food I know I've
been teasing you with dinner like get
some
dinner um is this whole concept of bug
Bounty motivation and you you've shared
with me while you've been here uh you
know maybe when we're chilling in the
hot tub or or you know relaxing um that
you struggled a little bit with
motivation with bug Bounty outside of
the live hacking events um and one of
the ways you tried to solve that is by
setting up this you know uh 50k bounties
in 50 days Challenge and and kind of
trying to motivate yourself and I'm sure
the Ambassador World Cup also helped um
but trying to motivate yourself outside
of live hacking events um do you so two
two-part question here okay first first
question is do you think live hacking
events H have sort of poisoned your
brain uh and and kind of made it more
difficult for you to focus on non-life
hacking event targets and then two what
are some ways that you have found to try
to motivate
yourself out outside of a live hacking
event yeah I don't know if it's the
challenge or if it's the public
accountability because the leaderboard
is open for everyone or if it's the
fight with friends but definitely every
gamification external factors helps you
to focus more and know because like I
said I have now 90 different programs
that I know we pay well if I focus on
them but how can you focus on 90
programs with 500 W domains and 250,000
sub domain M so that's like the question
where do I focus now oh wait I focus
here my Roi wouldn't be that good for
other programs so it's
like in Pocket they say EV you know
expected value do you want to play the
hand if you I mean do you expect how
much you could earn if you make this
play based on the probability and stuff
like in general I mean am I making the
right choice focusing on this program
when I have all of the other programs
are waiting so the best way to have the
best EV or the best our is like when
there is an event and everyone is
focused and you can get invite to the
next event if you do well so that's like
the best Roi that I can get I don't know
in real like on normal times we don't
know where is the best Roi to get I mean
maybe if someone tweets oh I got 100k
from epic games so I got 250k for maybe
the best Roi will be there at the moment
so it's it's all about the moment like
where would we find the best Roi at a
given time so some of the people I know
were looking at the activity feed on a
one just to see a programs who resolve
the bug to see okay they're alive let's
check them because they're active now we
can't do it because they changed some of
the in the activity but they will revert
it back I think but it's basically like
that I mean find a way to know which
programs are active paying if you can
make a competition or between people
like a league or something like you know
to to have extra extra motivation to do
better between between you and your
friends maybe you know for the F for the
B just for to focus with another person
so yeah I mean a lot of idea that I
don't have for but if anyone know so or
or maybe or maybe fly out to Virginia
and hang out with your friend in person
and do some hacking there yeah
competition and stuff that's good um
yeah it's a hard problem to solve the
bunk Bounty motivation thing and and I
kind of shared with you um while we were
talking about this that you know for me
it's it's a lot about forcing yourself
to start doing it and then from there
you get curious about the Target right
you you for me I I get that technical
curiosity that kind of grow
um and but in the beginning you really
got to force yourself to go you know
back down that deep dive again uh which
is definitely hard to do so it's a it's
a struggle that we all kind of deal with
and we'll continue to overcome as bug
bounty hunters but uh I'm sure it it
helps everyone who's listening to the
podcast to know that a top Hunter even a
top automation like yourself uh deals
with those sort of similar struggles so
thanks for sharing that no all right man
the time has come let's go get some
dinner I think I think that's it that's
a wrap okay much
[Music]
peace